bankcardservices.co.uk 2010-12-12

# Privacy - MBNA Online Card Services

## Privacy Statement

This is the privacy statement of MBNA. Whilst exploring the services offered through this and Websites owned by other members of the MBNA, please be alert for and review any specialised privacy statements and terms of use applicable to particular products or Websites, or portions thereof, as they may differ depending on group, company, product or service.

## Further Protection of Your Privacy Policies of other Service Providers

Whilst exploring the services offered through MBNA's Website, please be aware that other online retailers, partners, third party Internet sites, and third party services accessible through MBNA's Website have separate privacy and data collection policies and practices, which are independent of and may differ from MBNA's policies and practices. MBNA is not responsible or liable for these independent policies and practices. It is your responsibility to review them and decide whether such policies and practices satisfactorily protect your rights.

## Customer Privacy Is Important To Us.

At MBNA, we are committed to providing our Customers with the finest products backed by consistently top-quality service. However, we fully recognise the importance of keeping our Customers' personal and account information secure.

  * We use established and exacting security standards to protect Customer information from unauthorised access.
  * We verify the identity of our Customers through the use of personal passwords or other information before assisting them.
  * We also use vigilant protection measures in order to protect our Customers' accounts from fraudulent use.

## Personal Information

The MBNA Web server automatically recognises and records the domain name from which you access the Internet and the names of the pages you visited while at our site. In doing this, we do not gather or store any personal information about you. We do not store your electronic mail address (unless you choose to provide that to us). The information gathered may be used to improve the content of the MBNA Website and make it more useful. Any personal information which you provide to us when you apply for a product or hold an account with us will be used in accordance with the terms and conditions of the particular agreement which you have entered into with us and in accordance with data protection legislation in the United Kingdom and Ireland.

## Internet Safety

MBNA is committed to ensuring your personal and Account information is protected, both off and on the Internet. As a reminder:

  * MBNA will not disclose or request sensitive information in any unencrypted email communications (e.g., full account number and security passwords). If you should receive an email containing or asking for this type of sensitive information, please call us immediately at 0800 062 062 (UK) or 0818 409 511 (Ireland) prior to responding.
  * If you call MBNA or receive a call from MBNA, please remember we will never ask you to provide us with your online account password.
  * Any emails sent from MBNA, including Customer Satisfaction emails and new product offers, would require you to successfully log on to Online Card Services before entering any Account or personal information. We do not request that personal information be sent via email.
  * Email hoaxes are becoming commonplace on the Internet. If you suspect that you have received a hoax email that appears to be from MBNA, do not click on any links that may be embedded in the message. Instead, please call us immediately at 0800 062 062 (UK) or 0818 409 511 (Ireland) and after speaking with us delete the email.

## Advertising Services

MBNA uses third party companies to show advertisements on our Website and other Websites. These companies help MBNA execute, optimise, and measure the effectiveness of our online banner advertising programs. These companies use cookies and non-personally identifiable information (for example, information that does not include name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visit to this and other Websites to measure advertising effectiveness and to provide advertisements about goods and services that may interest you. If you would like to learn more about these practices, view the privacy notices of these third party companies, or opt out of their use of non-personally identifiable information, [click here to learn more about MBNA's banner advertisements Opens new window ](http://www.mbna.co.uk/privacy/#q5).

MBNA's banner advertisements and online applications may contain small graphics with tags in them. These tags are not personally identifiable and work in conjunction with these cookies. These tags allow us to measure the effectiveness and response rates of our advertising.

##  Cookies, similar files and other technologies

Cookies are pieces of information stored directly on the computer you are using. MBNA, or our third-party advertising service providers, may place cookies or similar files on your hard drive for security purposes, to facilitate site navigation and to personalise your experience while visiting our site. Cookies allow us to collect technical and navigational information, such as browser type, time spent on our site and pages visited. Cookies allow us to select which of our advertisements or offers are most likely to appeal to you and display them while you are on MBNA websites. We may also use cookies in online advertising to track consumer responses to MBNA advertisements and we may use cookies or other files to track your use of other websites. Cookies and other technologies provide us the capability to monitor the use of our site so we can continually improve the design and functionality to better serve you. Cookies and similar files do not contain or capture unencrypted personally identifiable data.

If you do not accept these cookies, you may experience some inconvenience in your use of some online products. For example, for Online Card Services, we will not be able to recognise your computer and you will need to answer a challenge question each time you log on. You also may not receive advertising or other offers from us that are relevant to your interests and needs.

MBNA uses cookies in two ways:

  * **Web-browsing cookies**   
MBNA uses web-browsing cookies to display information more effectively to you and to gather data about the usage of our website. 
  * **Online Card Services cookies**   
Cookies are used for security purposes in conjunction with our SiteKey service to recognise your computer. Any time a cookie is used, personal information is encrypted and used solely to support your Online Card Services activity. 

## Similar files

MBNA also uses files called Flash Objects in connection with Online Card Services. This is used to help assure security as part of our SiteKey service. As with cookies, we never store personal information unless encrypted.

## Other technologies

Other technologies we use may capture customer specific data to help us understand how customers use our site and to assist us with resolving customers' questions regarding the use of our site.

## Information we collect 

When you visit this site, we may collect certain types of information from you, such as information you voluntarily provide via forms, surveys, applications, etc. We may also collect information about you from your online browsing and transactions, including your preferences, pages visited, technical information regarding your computer and operating systems, such as your internet protocol address, domain name and system configuration and settings. Please see the  _Cookies, similar files and other technologies_ section.

## Privacy Statement Changes

We may change this Privacy Statement from time to time. When such a change is made, we will post a revised version on this Website. Changes will be effective when they are posted. It is your responsibility to review this Privacy Statement from time to time to be aware of any such change. Your continued use of the service will indicate your agreement to any such change.

This Privacy Statement was last reviewed March 2010.

This Privacy Statement is published by MBNA registered in England under number 2783251. The registered office address is Stansfield House, Chester Business Park, Wrexham Road, Chester, CH4 9QQ. MBNA is at your service 24 hours a day, seven days a week and can be contacted via the telephone on 0800 062 062 (UK) or 0818 409 511 (Ireland) .
